scent restraint is the the practice of
non destruction yes all the time in a
way this is either intent on dental
exactly you're not like holding on to
your wakefulness in a rotten way
you're basically intent or not losing it
how you lose it you lose it by giving in
to a non wakeful intention so you cannot
accidentally lose your wakefulness
so even lapsing in terms of your
thoughts is something or similar it's
not necessarily you lost wakefulness you
lose wakefulness when you intentionally
give in to distraction or lust or anger
and inversion so that's why in relation
to the preview print well one of the
previous talks was to keep questioning
yourself your motivation so that your
own intentions can become transparent
and clear because you will know even if
sometimes people say oh you know I'm
engaged with like spreading the Dharma
but they're doing it their intentions
are rooted in the desire for distraction
is emphasized something to do giving
this this worldly purpose to my life
because otherwise just boredom and
anxiety sets in and it's too much to
handle and in that case that's not the
Dharma although you might be actually
parroting the Buddha's words and
published in the Buddhist words it's not
the actual dama which is always non
aversion not non green on a version on
delusion non distraction wakefulness and
knowledge
the only thing he knows not being able
to just relax exactly though you can
relax perfectly you can actually you
would be relaxed all the time if you can
start discerning your intentions and
then just you don't have to and that's
the problem and people don't discern
intentions they tend to be either
indulge Amal or dismiss them all if they
don't see anything in between if a
person starts discerning their own
motivation their own intentions then you
know actually these intentions are not
rooted in greed nor aversion or delusion
fine the problem that's how you get
relaxed so only you have to abandon
those that are rooted in design for
distraction these are for sensuality
design for a version and so when you
when it coming from you know just
relaxing you into greed or what you take
relaxing into delusion that's all you
know initially the only notion of
relaxation is relaxation of distraction
which in half but that's yeah that that
that type of relaxation needs to be
benefited some fertilisation really
or you can call it annexation but it's
not peace it is fully controlled by a
fully dependent upon it like watching
watching a movie shows has come for the
sound science last one basically you're
out through your senses you might not
necessarily be actively pursuing the
sensual the full-on sensual pleasures
but it's still bound we decide sound
smell taste touches which means is still
with stupid in the central domain that's
why it's not just you have to abandon
the the obvious course central it you
also have to abandon distraction that
you've been gaining through your senses
but when I say abandon doesn't mean you
obliterate any notion of your senses and
denied I just mean make sure that if you
are engaging that motivation the
intentions behind that engagement are is
not rooted in greed aversion delusion
which basically delusion equals wanting
destruction non wait that's it all of
those which would contribute to non
wakefulness so that's it and then
automatically if it's not those then
it's automatically wakefulness
that's why you don't you're not doing
the wakefulness you're developing it
basically by preventing non wakefulness
to overwhelm you in like intentionally
to give in to it so you prevent that and
then you automatically wake
then become exactly because you're not
doing it it's not a method or something
to uphold constantly every second of
your life that's how you get truly
relaxed truly peaceful because it's
effortless it takes effort to give in to
intentions to do things upon them be it
central or non central but if you all
you do is just abstain from the effort
of engaging with sensuality aversion
distraction then your experience is
automatically effortless and wakeful and
then within that well you'll know
exactly what to do